Hello everyone, welcome
back to English Pod.
My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today
we're going to be going
to one of those places
that is really common,
right? That's right.
We're going to the hair salon. The hair
salon or maybe also called a barber shop.
I guess in this case it's a
barber shop because it's a man
who's getting a haircut.
Okay, so before we see
what happens in this
barber shop, let's take
a look at some of the vocabulary we
might encounter in vocabulary preview.
Very cabaret preview. Okay, we're
going to look at two words that
you'll hear in this dialogue
and the first one is trim.
Trim. A trim. All right,
so when you trim
something, you cut
just a little bit of it.
All right, so if I go to the
hair salon to get a trim,
you are going to cut
only a little bit of your hair.
Okay, you're not going to
change the style and make
it look different.
Okay, so a trim.
And I think here we've seen that
it can be a verb and a noun, right?
Okay, so I'm going
to get a trim. Yes.
Or I want you to trim
my hair. That's right.
All right, and what about our
next word? Fancy. Fancy. Fancy.
So fancy. Now we know
that this word maybe is
related to something
like luxury or formal or
something like that. Right,
but in this case or in this
context, we're going to be
using it a little bit different.
That's right. Here
in this dialogue,
we'll hear nothing too fancy
or nothing too complicated.
Nothing too different.
Okay, so we don't want
anything too fancy. All
right, but with these two
words in mind, I think
we're ready to listen to
the dialogue. Hello
there. Come on in.
Don't just stand there. Come
and take a seat. Um, okay. Well,
I just want a trim.
Nothing too fancy.
Oh my gosh. Your hair is
amazing. So silky. So shiny.
I am going to work
my magic on your hair.
You hear me. You are going
to look like a million box.
Okay. Um, can you
make sure my sideburns
are even and you just
take a little at the top?
Don't you worry. I'll
take care of everything.
Oh my god. I just
love your curly hair.
It's so fluffy and cute. You
should totally let it grow out.
An afro would look great on you.
Um, no. Okay, but you are
going to be my masterpiece.
Okay, so I think
maybe his haircut is not
quite what he expected.
I think he trusted the
stylist a little bit too much.
I think the stylist had
too many red boulders.
Maybe very hyper. Maybe
that was his problem. All right.
So why don't we take a
look now at some of the
language that we saw
in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. So I
guess the stylist really thought
this guy had nice hair,
right? Yeah, we heard how he
described his hair. He
said it was so silky, silky.
Silky. All right. So we
know the word silk.
Mm hmm. A material very
soft and smooth material.
And when something is silky,
um, it's very soft and smooth.
All right. So silky
hair or silky skin.
All right. So silky. So
he said he had silky and
shiny hair, shiny,
shiny, shiny. All right.
So we know what shiny
is. Do we? Guess we do.
Okay, what? So something
that is shiny is you can
see yourself in it like gold
is shiny or silver is shiny.
All right. Or if you look in the
back of a CD, it's shiny. Yeah.
So the light bounces off
things that are shiny. All right.
Now getting into more
hairstyle vocabulary, he
wanted to make sure that his
sideburns were even sideburns.
All right. So
sideburns. All right.
Well sideburns are things
that men have, right?
All right. Women don't have sideburns.
No. Okay. So it's kind of like a beard.
And it's the hair that grows
on your cheeks near your ears.
Okay. Those are
your sideburns. Yes.
And now also the
hairstylist suggested that he
should let his hair grow
out grow out grow out,
grow out, let your
hair grow out. All right.
So what does that mean exactly
make let your hair get longer?
So you can say
let your hair grow.
Yeah. But I guess it's
more common to hear
let your hair grow out. Well, maybe it just
means something a little bit different.
If I let my hair grow, I
might let it grow a little bit,
make it a little bit
longer. But if I let my hair
grow out, maybe it's short
now and I'll let it get really long.
Okay. So to let your hair grow out is
to really change the length. All right.
Very good. So let your hair
grow out and our last word on
language takeaway
today, Afro Afro Afro.
So if this guy let his curly hair
grow out, he would have an Afro.
And Afro. Right. So now this hairstyle
was very popular in the 70s. That's right.
It's like a big round curly fluffy
ball of hair. Exactly. So that's in Afro.
We'll post some pictures
on the website for you
to get a clear idea
of what this looks like.
All right. So I think now we are ready to
listen to our dialogue for the second time.
And then we'll come back
and look at some phrases.
Hello there. Come on
in. Don't just stand there.
Come and take a seat.
Um, okay. Well, I just want to
trim nothing too
fancy. Oh my gosh.
Your hair is amazing. So silky.
So shiny. I am going to work my
magic on your hair. You hear me? You are
going to look like a million bucks. Okay.
Um, can you make sure my
sideburns are even and you just
take a little off the top. Don't you worry,
I'll take care of everything. Oh my God.
I just love your curly
hair. It's so fluffy and cute.
You should totally
let it grow out.
And Afro would look great on
you. Um, no. Okay. But you're
going to be my masterpiece.
Okay. So we have some
phrases here that you
might hear in a hair salon
or in a barber shop.
So why don't we look at
those now in fluency
builder? Fluency builder.
The hairstylist said
don't just stand there.
Don't just stand there. All
right. Don't just stand there.
So this is an interesting
phrase, Marco.
I mean, it's made up of
really simple words, right?
Right. But actually those words make
it an order that's a little bit different.
So why don't we hear a few examples to
help us understand how to use this phrase?
Example one. Don't just stand there.
Help me take these boxes into the house.
Example two, the house is on fire. Then
just stop there. Go to fire department.
Example three. Don't just stand
there in the rain. Come inside.
Okay. So basically we
can understand that if
somebody tells you don't just stand there,
they are expecting you to do something.
We might use this phrase
when somebody is not doing
what we think they should do.
Okay. When action is required.
Exactly. Okay. So
why don't we move on
to our next phrase now?
Look like a million bucks.
You look like a million
bucks. So when someone
looks like a million bucks,
they look really, really good.
Yeah. So that is a
very common way of
just saying you look very
good or something looks
like a million bucks. So it can
be for a person or a thing, right?
Exactly. Okay. And
our final phrase
and this one is really
common in in barber shops.
Take a little off the top.
So that basically means
cut a little bit on top.
Exactly. And now can I say
take a little off the sides?
Yeah, you can say that as well.
All right. So take
a little off the top.
Take a little off the sides.
Okay. So with all this great
haircutting language, why don't we
listen to our dialogue one last time?
Hello there. Come on
in. Don't just stand there.
Come and take a seat.
Okay. Well, I just want to trim
that thing to fancy. Oh my gosh.
Your hair is amazing. So silky.
So shiny. I am going to work my
magic on your hair. You hear me. You are
going to look like a million bucks. Okay.
Can you make sure my
sideburns are even and you
just take a little off the
top? Don't you worry.
I'll take care of
everything. Oh my God.
I just love your curly
hair. It's so fluffy and cute.
You should totally let it
grow out. An afro would
look great on you. No.
Okay, but you are going to be
my master piece. All
right. So now talking
about hairstyles and
different types of hair,
there are some interesting ones that
maybe aren't so fashionable anymore. Yeah.
I'm actually English has a lot of
really cool words to describe haircut.
So let's start with
a couple of them.
For example, a mullet.
A mullet. So this is when
your hair is really short on
top and really long in the back.
Right. So the sides
and the top are
really short, but in the
back you have long hair.
Yeah. In Canada, we call that a Shorty
Shorty Longback. Shorty Longback. Yeah.
We also call it hockey
hair. Hockey hair or
even all business up
front, all party behind.
Well, Canadians are obviously
very into this hairstyle.
It's unfortunately true.
All right, we also have for example
a Mohawk. Popular amongst
the punk rock kids.
Exactly. So you shave your
head on the sides, but
you leave a little like
stripe of long hair on top.
I'm sticking up long hair.
Okay, and that's a Mohawk.
What about a flat top? Oh,
popular with law enforcement
agents and serial
killers. So basically it's
short hair on the sides
and short and flat hair
on the top. Right. So
you don't take a box.
Right. You have flat.
Kind of like your haircut.
I do not have a flat top for all of you out
there, but I did used to have a crew cut.
Oh, crew cut. A crew cut. Yeah.
Like an army haircut. Right.
So very short on the sides
and a little bit long
on top. Yeah. Okay.
Um, and our last one, my actual
personal least favorite haircuts.
Dreadlocks.
Dreadlocks. All right.
So, so dreadlocks are
like knots of hair. Yeah.
It looks like you haven't washed
your hair in about seven years.
Right. Those are dreadlocks
very popular among
like Rastafarian or
like young hippie kids.
Yeah. Hippies, right? Very
good. So about in your
countries, what different
hairstyles are popular there?
I know that Japanese hairstyles
are really cool. Yeah. That's right.
Japanese haircuts can
be pretty awesome. Right.
So tell us all about it.
Come to our website,
post some pictures. And also, if you
have any questions or doubts, let us know.
Well, thanks for downloading this
lesson, you guys. And until next time, bye.
[Music]